Let’s head into the final levels of exploit-exercises protostar.
让我们进入 exploit-exercises protostar 练习的最后一个阶段。
These levels are a little bit more developed and are on the level of very easy pwnable
这些级别挑战，稍微有点提升了，且是在非常简单的，
CTF challenges.
可编程的CTF挑战。
Let’s have a look at final level 0.
让我们来看看，final level 0。
The network setup is basically the same like from the previous challenges, so if you are
网络设置，基本上与以前的挑战相同，
not familiar with these custom functions you should watch the previous videos where we
因此，如果您是不熟悉这些自定义函数，
figure out what they do.
您应该在上集中，弄清楚他们在做什么。
So, when a client connects to this service running on port 2995, it will call this function
因此，当客户端连接到，运行在端口2995上的服务时，
get_username.
它将调用此函数 get_username。
This function has a local 512 byte big buffer which is overwritten with 0.
此函数有一个512字节的本地大缓冲区，该缓冲区被 0 覆盖。
Then gets is used to read data from the user into the buffer.
然后，用 gets 将数据从用户，读取到缓冲区中。
And as we have learned many episodes ago, gets is a dangerous function.
正如我们之前视频中，所了解的，get是一个危险的函数。
So this is obviously our buffer overflow.
显然，这是我们的缓冲区溢出。
Then it checks if there is a newline or carriage return and if so, would overwrite it with
然后，它检查是否有换行符或回车符，
a 0.
如果有，就用一个 0 覆盖。
After that is a loop, which will go over the buffer and call toupper on every character.
之后是一个循环，它将遍历缓冲区，并对每个字符调用 toupper。
Then the function returns.
之后，函数返回。
This means we should be able to overwrite the return pointer of this function and redirect
这意味着，我们应该能够覆盖这个函数的返回指针，
code execution.
并重定向代码执行。
We only have one issue, and that is that the data we would use to overflow would be transformed
我们只有一个问题，那就是我们将用于溢出的数据，
to uppercase.
将被转换大写字母。
This means our shellcode, as well as the address we use to overwrite the instruction pointer
就是，我们的 shellcode，还有当使用 toupper 时，
on the stack have to not change when toupper is used.
我们用来覆盖栈上指令指针的地址，不可更改。
Meaning, you cannot use lower-case ascii characters.
也就是说，不能使用小写的ASCII字符。
Or is there maybe a trick how we can get around this restriction?
或者说，有没有一个技巧，可以让我们绕过这个限制？
Let’s think about this and work our way backwards.
让我们考虑一下这个问题，同时往下看。
So what condition has to be true in order that toupper is not used on our input.
所以，为了不在我们的输入中，使用 toupper，必须满足什么条件。
Well the for loop uses strlen to determine on how many bytes it will do this.
for循环使用 strlen 来确定，执行操作的字节数。
And strlen counts all bytes until in finds a null byte.
strlen 计算所有字节，直到在里面，找到一个空字节。
So if we manage to somehow get a null byte before our actual overflow and shellcode,
所以，如果我们设法在实际溢出和 shellcode 之前，得到一个空字节，
we would be fine.
我们就会没事的。
Ok, how could we get a null byte in there.
好吧，我们怎么能得到一个空字节呢？
If you check the man page of gets you will see, that gets reads everything until it a
如果你查看 gets 的手册页，你会看到，
newline or EOF.
它会读取所有内容，直到换行或EOF。
This means gets will have no issue of reading a null-byte.
这意味着,gets将不会有读取空字节的问题。
Easy.
那就简单。
So we can completly ignore the to uppercase stuff.
我们可以完全忽略变为大写的内容。
And just for creativity reasons, you could also abuse the null-byte replacement of the
出于创造性的原因，您还可以把回车符，
carriage return.
换成空字节。
Let’s say the input would use strcpy, thus also stopping at a null byte, you could use
假设，输入将使用 strcpy，因此也是以空字节结尾的，
a carriage return instead, which will then afterwards get replaced by a null byte.
您可以使用一个回车替代，然后再用一个空字节替换。
So that would also work.
所以，这也是可行的。
The buffer is 512 bytes big, so let’s use that knwoledge to create a simple proof of
缓冲区是512字节大，所以让，我们集中知识，
concept buffer overflow.
创建一个简单概念的缓冲区溢出。
We can use python with -c, to directly write a short script in the argument.
我们可以使用 python 和-c，直接在参数中，编写一个简短的脚本。
So we could print like 510 lowercase a, and then we can later see that these were modified
所以，我们可以打印510个小写字母A，然后。我们可以看到
to be uppercase.
它们被修改为大写。
Then we append a nullbyte and continue with a typical alphabet so we can recognize how
然后，我们附加一个空字节，继续使用一个典型的字母表，
to overflow the instruction pointer.
这样我们就可以识别指令指针是怎么溢出的。
We can also make the alphabet lowercase, to proof that it will not be transformed to uppercase
我们也可以把字母表改成小写，以证明在空字节之后，
after the nullbyte.
它不会被转换成大写。
Like with the previous networking challenges we can connect to the service on port 2995
和以前的网络挑战一样，我们可以连接到端口2995上的服务
with netcat.
使用 netcat。
So we can simply pipe the output of our python one-liner to netcat as well.
所以，我们也可以简单将python一行程序的输出，通过管道传输到netcat。
We don’t see the output “No such user… “ like before.
我们没有像以前那样看到“没有这样的用户…”输出。
And the code shows us that it would be printed after the return in main, thus we can assume
代码告诉我们，它将在 main 返回之后被打印，因此我们可以假设，
we successfully overwrote the instruction pointer and crashed the program.
我们成功地重写了指令指针，并使程序崩溃。
But how do we debug this now?
但是，我们现在如何调试它呢？
If you have a look at the description of the protostar VM, you will see here a headline
如果你看一下 protostar 虚拟机的描述，。
called core files.
你会在这里看到一个标题，称为核心文件。
It says that the filename pattern is set to /tmp/ something.
它说，文件名模式设置为 /tmp/something。
This means that core dumps are stored in tmp.
这意味着，核心日志，存储在 tmp 中。
And when we have a look at the content of /tmp/ we will see a core file we just produced.
当我们查看 /tmp/ 的内容时，我们将看到一个刚刚生成的核心文件。
They belong to root, so let’s switch to root so we can work with them.
它们属于根权限，所以让我们切换到根权限，这样我们就可以使用它们了。
But what are core files?
但是什么是核心文件？
Let’s ask the linux manual with `man core`.
让我们用“man core”，来询问Linux手册。
The default action of certain signals is to cause a process to terminate and produce a
某些信号的默认动作，是使进程终止，并产生一个核心日志文件，
core dump file, a disk file containing an image of the process's memory at the time
就是一个包含终止进程的，
of termination.
内存图像的磁盘文件。
This sounds good, if we get the state of the memory when it crashed, we should be able
这听起来不错，如果我们得到了它崩溃时的内存状态，
to get a lot of information about our buffer overflow.
我们应该能够获取大量关于缓冲区溢出的信息。
This image can be used in a debugger (e.g., gdb(1)) to inspect the state of the program
此图像可在调试器（例如，gdb（1））中，用于检查，
at the time that it terminated.
程序在它终止时候的状态。
Oh wow, we can use gdb to look at these and we area already very familiar with how to
哦，哇，我们可以用gdb来看看这些，
use gdb.
我们已经非常熟悉如何使用 gdb 。
A list of the signals which cause a process to dump core can be found in signal(7).
在 signal（7）中，可以找到导致，进程转储核心的信号(signal)列表。
Ok, interesting.
好的，很有趣。
Apparently the process received a signal because it did produce a core file, right?
显然，进程收到了一个信号，因为它确实产生了一个核心文件，对吗？
So to understand this properly, let’s also try to understand what signals are.
为了正确理解这一点，让我们也试着理解什么是信号。
Notice the 7 in brackets after signal, this is important to reference the correct page
注意信号后括号中的 7 ，这很重要，
about signal in the manual.
关乎哪张参考手册页面。
so `man 7 signal`.
所以“man 7 signal”。
Let’s have a look at the standard signals further down.
让我们再往下看一下标准信号。
Linux supports the standard signals listed below.
Linux支持下面列出的标准信号。
Several signal numbers are architecture-dependent, as indicated in the "Value" column.
如“Value”一栏所示，几个信号数字取决于体系结构。
Mhh, so signals can be different on different architectures.
嗯，所以信号在不同的架构上，是不同的。
So if it is an intel, arm or sparc processor this might make a difference, bug generally
因此，如果它是一个Intel、ARM或SPARC处理器，这可能会有所不同，
this tells us, that signals could have something to do with very low-level CPU and hardware
bug通常告诉我们，信号可能与，
features.
非常低级别的CPU和硬件特征有关。
Let’s have a look at the list of signals.
让我们看看信号列表。
For example SIGINT is a signal you have used many many times, it’s an interrupt from
例如， SIGINT 是一个多次使用的信号，
the keyboard, this happens when you press control+C.
它是来自键盘，当你按下Control+C时，会发生这种情况。
Or remember how you sometimes can get illegal instruction when you jump into invalid code,
或记住，当你跳入无效的代码时，你有时是如何得到非法指令的，
a SIGILL, that’s also a signal.
一个 SIGILL ，这也是一个信号。
Which obviously must have been triggered from the CPU which couldn’t make sense of an
很明显，这一定是由CPU触发的，
instruction.
表示，它无法理解指令。
Or our favorite syscall, SIGSEGV, a segfault.
或者我们最喜欢的 syscall，SIGSEGV，一个分段错误。
Trigegred from an illigel memory reference, for example when you jump to non-existing
从非法内存引用中，触发，例如当您跳转到不存在的
memory.
内存。
Or try to write to non existing memory.
或者，尝试写入不存在的内存。
Which obviously is also triggered by low level hardware when you try to execute bad stuff.
很明显，都是再你试图执行坏的东西时，这也是由低级硬件触发的。
This line here is also interesting: The signals SIGKILL and SIGSTOP cannot be caught, blocked,
这里的这一行也很有趣：信号 SIGKILL 和 SIGSTOP 不能被捕获、阻止，
or ignored.
或者忽略。
This means most of these signals can be caught by the process.
这意味着，这些信号中的大部分都可以被进程捕获。
You have actually experience this before too, when you run a process in gdb, and you forgot
在 gdb 中运行一个进程时，您实际上，也经历过这种情况，但是您忘记了
to set a breakpoint and the process is just running, you can use CTRL+C to break back
若要设置断点，且进程正在运行，
into gdb.
可以使用ctrl+c 返回，进入 gdb 。
You sent a SIGINT to the process which instead of quitting, had a signal handler set up to
这时，您是向进程发送了一个 SIGINT，而不是退出，会有一个信号处理程序，
catch it and perform a different action.
设置为抓住信号，并执行不同的操作。
So signals are kind of like interrupts for processes by the kernel.
所以，信号有点像内核对进程的中断。
Certain events like memory access fails, pressing CTRL+C or also killing a process causeses
某些事件（如内存访问失败、按 ctrl+c 或同时终止进程）会导致，
the kernel to send a signal to a process.
内核向进程发送一个信号。
Unhandled signals usually cause the process to die, but a process can also set up signal
未处理的信号，通常会导致进程死亡，但进程也可以设置信号处理程序
handlers to perform certain actions when it receives these signals.
，在接收到这些信号时，执行某些操作。
So.
所以。
In our case, when we overflow EIP on the stack, and the function returns a segmentation fault
在我们的例子中，当我们在栈上，溢出 eip 时，函数返回，出现的一个分段错误，
is raised and a signal is triggered.
并触发信号。
The process doesn’t handle it and is killed by the kernel.
进程若不处理它，就被内核杀死。
At the same time a core dump file is created to save the state of the process that caused
同时，创建一个核心转储文件，
this signal.
来保存导致这个信号的状态。
So now let’s use gdb to see what happened.
现在让我们用gdb，来看看发生了什么。
Like before you simply specify the binary as a first argument but then you add the core
像前面一样，只需将二进制文件指定为第一个参数，
file as a second argument.
然后，添加核心文件作为第二个参数。
And you see immediately when gdb opens, the message that the process terminated due to
当gdb打开时，会立即看到进程由于
signal 11, a segmentation fault.
信号11，分段错误。
We can also look at the registers and see the value of eip.
我们还可以查看寄存器，并查看 eip 的值。
And those are definitely our characters we have entered.
这些绝对是我们已经输入的字符。
We can also explore the stack with examining the stack pointer.
我们还可以通过检查栈指针，来探索栈。
You can see that having these core files is extremely useful.
您可以看到，拥有这些核心文件非常有用。
Now we know which characters caused an overflow and we can now calculate the offset to the
现在我们知道哪些字符导致了溢出，
instruction pointer on the stack.
我们可以计算到栈上指令指针的偏移。
Another way to debug this further is to use gdb to attach to the already running process.
另一种进一步调试的方法是，使用 gdb 附加到已经运行的进程。
Make sure you are root.
确保你是根权限。
Simply find the process id and call gdb with -p and the pid.
只需找到进程id，并使用 -p 和 pid 调用gdb。
As you can see the process is currently in accept waiting for a client to connect.
如您所见，进程当前处于接受状态，等待客户端连接。
But when we send our PoC overflow, we don’t see a segfault.
但，当我们发送PoC溢出时，我们看不到分段错误。
That’s because if you remember, this process creates a fork, a new process, to handle the
如果您还记得的话，这是因为该进程会创建一个分叉，一个新的进程，
client.
来处理客户端。
And we always stay in the parent.
我们总是呆在父进程身边。
But we can set in gdb the follow-fork-mode to child, and when we now continue and send
但是，我们可以在gdb中，follow fork 模式设置为 child，
the long input, we get the segfault.
若我们现在继续，并发送长的输入，我们会得到了分段错误。
Awesome, now you have everything in place to develop the full exploit.
太棒了，现在你已经准备好全部的一切，开发完整的漏洞。